providence.edu 2019-03-31

# Providence College Privacy Policy – Providence College

[Site Home](https://www.providence.edu/) > **Providence College Privacy Policy**

## Protecting Privacy

Providence College is committed to protecting the privacy of information provided by visitors to our website. The personal information that you provide on our website will be used expressly for the purpose of responding to your inquiry or processing the intended online transaction. We may communicate with you to provide you with additional information related to your request or transaction, or related to College news or updates. It will not be used for any other commercial or philanthropic purpose.. Opt-out or unsubscribe options are available.

The College uses third-party sites for some of its services. Most of these sites are governed by their own privacy policy; otherwise, they have an agreement with the College to honor our privacy standards. The College may provide aggregated statistical data to reputable third-party vendors, but those data will include no personally identifiable information.

Providence College does, upon explicit request of users, share information with other parties and gather information from other private data providers. For example, the College receives test scores from testing agencies and will send transcripts to other educational institutions. This action is taken only at the request of users (persons to whom the information applies).

Providence College collects and aggregates anonymous user traffic information, and uses the data to observe traffic patterns across our websites in order to optimize and create a better experience for users. This information is used solely for this purpose and is shared with offices across campus.

Providence College may release information when we believe, in good faith, that such release is reasonably necessary to enforce law, to enforce or apply the terms of any of our user agreements, or to protect personal safety or property rights. We will share personally identifiable information about you when one or more of the following conditions apply: we have your consent to share the information; we respond to or comply with subpoenas, court orders, legal process, or regulations; or we employ other companies to perform functions on our behalf, such as processing credit card payments. Such companies have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use this information for other purposes.

The College has taken reasonable measures to protect personal information from loss, misuse, alteration, or unauthorized access; however, no website security procedures are foolproof. Any personal information you submit to Providence College via its website is submitted at your own risk and the College will not be liable to you for any breach of security or inadvertent disclosure of your personal information.

Users accessing personal information do so via secure server software (SSL), which encrypts information users provide before we receive it. As effective as encryption technology is, however, no security system is completely impenetrable; thus, we cannot guarantee absolute security of our database or that information you provide will not be intercepted while transmitted to us over the Internet.

Several of our sites enable users to pay for services or products online with a credit card. Unless otherwise noted, these transactions are encrypted. In accordance with College policy, confidential information provided in these transactions is used only for the purposes described in that transaction and at that site.

Providence College makes forums, message boards, and news groups available to its users. The College does not ordinarily log public chat sessions; however, any information that is disclosed via the above communication methods becomes public information and users should exercise caution when deciding to disclose confidential information in such manner.

At various times, online surveys are being conducted on the College’s website. Confidential information gathered in such online surveys is used only for the purposes (research or otherwise) indicated in the survey. Unless otherwise noted, answers provided by responders are confidential and individual responses will be not improperly disclosed. Aggregate (and non-personally identifiable data) from surveys may be shared with external third parties.

Some sections of our website use cookies to help us know more about our visitors, including their search history. We do not collect personally identifiable information from cookies. Your search browser should permit you to disable or block the use of cookies.

## Unsubscribe Processes

### Alumni & Institutional Advancement

The College is working with third parties to collect user data for conversion tracking and to serve ads targeted to users’ interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising, use your browser’s Do Not Track function. Twitter users can also change their advertising settings to opt out.

### School of Continuing Education

To unsubscribe from the SCE email list, please send an email to [sce@providence.edu](mailto:sce@providence.edu). Please include “unsubscribe” in your subject line.
